Guide to the Collection of Bookplates by Hans Ranzoni the Younger
Yale University Arts Library
Collection of Bookplates by Hans Ranzoni the Younger
1928-1943
BKP 71
Yale University Arts Library
0.42
(1 box)
The collection contains bookplates by Hans Ranzoni the Younger, an Austrian graphic artist and engraver.
Ranzoni, Hans, 1896-1991
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Yale Bookplate Collection was formerly housed in Sterling Memorial Library. The collection was incorporated into the Arts of the Book Collection in 1984 and then moved to the Seeley G. Mudd Library in 1990. In 2011 it was transferred to the Robert B. Haas Family Arts Library.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Hans Ranzoni the Younger (1896-1991) was an Austrian graphic artist and engraver, active in Vienna. In addition to designing bookplates, he created other illustrations as well as stamp designs.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains bookplates by Hans Ranzoni the Younger, an Austrian graphic artist and engraver. In addition to ex-libris, the collection also contains greeting cards, business cards, and postage stamps designed by Ranzoni.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: I. Bookplates – Individuals. II. Bookplates – Duplicates. III. Other Works.
Bookplates; Bookplates; Greeting cards; Postage stamps; Ranzoni, Hans, 1896-1991
- Bookplates – Individuals, Series I
  Arrangement
  Arranged in alphabetical order by the patron's last name.
  - Altmann – Forgács, 1928-1930 undated; 7 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Grünfeld – Latscher, 1930-1937 undated; 7 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Lichtenstein – Pijnenborg, 1929-1932 undated; 6 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Rupp – Stosius, 1933-1939 undated; 5 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Vogt – Weber, 1933-1935 undated; 4 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Bookplates – Duplicates, Series II
  - Birnholz – Palme, 1930-1932 undated; 6 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    General note
    Bookplates are not mounted.
- Other Works, Series III
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains various business cards, greeting cards, and stamps designed by Ranzoni.
  - Lauterbach – Winger, 1929-1940 undated; 9 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Also includes personal thank-you cards designed and used by Ranzoni.
  - Stamps, 1941 1943; 3 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Stamps for the "Deutsches Reich," including a Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart commemorative stamp and two stamps bearing a horse design for the "Grosser Preis von Wien 1943 Freudenau."